MALKA ADITHYA

Automation Test Engineer

adithyamalka6@gmail.com



+917032140267

Dedicated and skilled Software Test Engineer with 3.1 years of experience in test automation using Selenium, Maven, and TestNG of various web applications. Testing of various aspects of the frontend like form validation, navigation, redirection, resource checking. Collaborated with crossfunctional teams and customers to gather and define testing requirements, ensuring alignment with project goals and user expectations

Skills

- lava
- Selenium

Maven

TestNG

- Cucumber
- SoapUI

- Postman
- Linux

Experience

Mphasis (Client- Bank of Queensland(BoQ)): Associate Test Engineer

2021 - 2022

- Conducted automation testing on web applications using Selenium and TestNG, executing test scripts on Chrome and Firefox, and leveraging Selenium WebDriver for comprehensive end-to-end testing.
- Proficient in identifying dynamic element using locators and Xpath, along with expertise in TestNG annotations
- Developed automated test scripts to validate form submissions and various input scenarios, as well as designed tests to verify URL redirection, ensuring users are directed to the correct pages after specific actions.
- Experience in integrating selenium WebDriver into the maven project and managing it's dependencies in the POM file for consistency across testing environment
- Experienced in configuring and executing tests in parallel using TestNG's parallel execution capabilities improving overall efficiency of testing
- Collaborated with teams and customers to understand testing requirements, track client requests, and write test cases based on those requirements.
- Analyzed project documents to understand the requirements and identify errors, and prepared corresponding test estimation and test plan documents. Actively participated in developing test scripts, debugging, executing tests, and reporting defects.
- Performing regression testing of all the applications in integrated core banking release in both System Integration testing and User acceptance testing.
- Performing functional testing in both SIT and UAT phases to ensure the reliability and functionality of the application, particularly for small initiatives.

- Experience in writing the SQL queries to fetch and analyze the data for testing and validation.
- Skilled in using SoapUI for functional and non-functional testing of REST and SOAP APIs. Developed and maintained test suites and test cases in SoapUI, automating APIs validation.
- Implemented data-driven testing by integrating external data sources to execute tests with multiple input sets, ensuring coverage of various scenarios.
- Created and implemented various assertions such as XPath, Contains, HTTP status code assertions in SoapUI to validate API responses.

Mphasis (Client- HPE): Test Engineer

2023 - Present

- Installing and performing tests such as load testing, Performance testing, Integration testing, Regression testing and validating functionality across different OS.
- Testing of Network Interface Cards on Windows and various versions of Linux such as SLES, Ubuntu, RHEL and VMware ESXI.
- Executing the test plan and reporting the progress via SPIRA and JIRA.
- Experience in Linux OS to install/upgrade firmware and drivers using package managers and various Linux tools to test functionality and performance of Network interface cards.
- Experienced in configuring BIOS to test drivers and firmware for network interface cards across various operating systems. Tested network integrated cards using the baseboard management controller (BMC) and integrated lights out (iLO).'
- Utilized Postman to perform GET requests for API testing, validating the response data, status codes and headers to ensure proper functionality.

Appreciation

- Recognized by clients for proactively identifying and addressing a potential issue in a testcase where an empty statement was generated due to absence of transactions, highlighting attention to detail and perseverance.
- Commended by manager on Accolade platform for effectively managing multiple small initiatives alongside a core banking release, demonstrating strong multitasking and project management capabilities.
- Acknowledged by manager on Accolade platform for identifying critical bugs in data processing units and cross-training the team, contributing to enhanced team performance.

Education

B. Tech from Institute of Aeronautical Engineering

2017-2021

Electronics and Communication Engineering with CGPA of 8.04